# Haruna Ahmadu Bashiru

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Lagos, Nigeria Age: 24 +234 703 477 6388

akhmadharuna@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/comm/in/haruna-ahmadu-0a9991153

http://github.com/sleemkeen

#### **BIOGRAPHY**

Hi I'm Ahmadu

I am a full stack web developer from Kano state, Nigeria.

I am highly motivated and creative web developer with varied experience in web and mobile development. Successfully implemented numerous web apps, mobile apps, and APIs. A fast learner and self-starter with a persistent attitude towards systematic problem solving. A team player with excellent people skills.

#### **TECHNOLOGY**

Languages and Frameworks

Python, PHP(Laravel and Cakephp), JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, React, AngularJS, Webpack, Gulp, JSON, APIs and Vue, Wordpress.

Tools

Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Chrome Dev Tools, Git, Postman, MAMP, Xcode, Wordpress, Sublime Text, Google Analytics, DNS, AWS, Heroku, DigitalOcean, Bower, npm, Yarn, slack.

Databases

MySQL, MongoDB.

#### **Experience**

Full Stack Software Engineer (remote)

Dookita | Nigeria, Lagos | February 2018 – March 2018

Worked with a team of 3, using Slack app to communicate. Developed API using PHP/Laravel with VueJs to develop an online platform for medical doctors and patients. I also used react native to build android application for the platform.

#### Senior Full-Stack Developer

Instantcars | Nigeria, Lagos | July 2017 - Sept 2017

Instantcars is a startup, founded in 2017. They build an online platform to hire cars. I improved the user experience on the Front-End interface and redesigned it according to Visual Management and Usability principles, to provide an easier navigation and a better visibility on the information. I developed with Bootstrap, Angular, CSS3 & HTML5 and PHP (Laravel) as the backend.

## Full Stack Software Engineer (remote)

domail | Lagos, Ng | August 2015 - May 2016

Worked as a backend developer at domail. We developed an online email platform using jquery and laravel(php), then subsequently we used angularjs version 1.x to build the admin dashboard

## Freelance Senior Web Engineer

Nigerian Institute of Arbitrators (Nicarb) | Nigeria, Lagos | Jan 2014 - Oct 2017

Designed the institute website and developing a staff management platform to manage their staff, I developed with Bootstrap, cakephp and jquery.

## **Software Engineering Concepts**

Agile Methodologies, Object-oriented Design, REST, Test-Driven Design, Mvc.

#### **Education**

Bsc in computer science, UNIVERSITY OF LAGOS – 2015 till Date

Higher national diploma in Civil Engineering, YABA COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY 2013-2015

National diploma in Civil Engineering, YABA COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY 2010-2012

**Hobbies and Interest** 

Gaming

Cinema

Music

**Travelling**